{"data":[{"question":"Historians will never agree completely the effects of ________ the world's first atomic bomb ________ the World War II.","a":"drop \/ to end","b":"dropping \/ to be ended","c":"dropping \/ to end","d":"drop \/ end","answer":"3","explain":"\n- Preposition (by, of, in, on...) + Verb_ing\/noun.\u00a0\n- To: used when you talk about the purposes","category":"3","subcategorylv1":"19","subcategorylv2":"23","type":"1"},{"question":"She was unable to speak from ________.","a":"fear","b":"fearsome","c":"fearful","d":"fearless","answer":"1","explain":"\n- Preposition (by, of, in, on...) + Verb_ing\/noun","category":"3","subcategorylv1":"19","subcategorylv2":"23","type":"1"},{"question":"We felt ashamed ________ his action.","a":"to","b":"of","c":"on","d":"for","answer":"2","explain":"\n \n- Feel ashamed of doing sth\/sth.","category":"3","subcategorylv1":"19","subcategorylv2":"23","type":"1"},{"question":"A good student must know ________.","a":"to study hard","b":"to be a good student","c":"how to study effectively","d":"the way of effectively in study","answer":"3","explain":"\n- Know how to do something: know the method of doing something\u00a0\n\u00a0","category":"3","subcategorylv1":"19","subcategorylv2":"23","type":"1"},{"question":"Radioactivity causes cancer and may ________ future generations.","a":"create","b":"affect","c":"develop","d":"even help","answer":"2","explain":"\n- Affect somebody or something: do something that produces an effect or change in something or in someone's situation.\u00a0","category":"3","subcategorylv1":"19","subcategorylv2":"23","type":"1"},{"question":"The pilot agreed to land the plane only ________ the hijackers threatened in shoot some of the passengers.","a":"which","b":"when","c":"that","d":"where","answer":"2","explain":"\n- When: used as a conjunction when you say that at what time something happens","category":"3","subcategorylv1":"19","subcategorylv2":"23","type":"1"},{"question":"We was delighted ________ you've won the first prize in the National mathematics competition.","a":"that","b":"when","c":"why","d":"where","answer":"1","explain":"\n- That: subject or object pronoun for people, animals and things in defining relative clauses (who or which are also possible).\u00a0\n- When: time; why: reason; where: place.","category":"3","subcategorylv1":"19","subcategorylv2":"23","type":"1"},{"question":"You were responsible ________ the error.","a":"to","b":"for","c":"on","d":"in","answer":"2","explain":"\n- To be responsible for.","category":"3","subcategorylv1":"19","subcategorylv2":"23","type":"1"},{"question":"He was ________ to prevent it.","a":"power","b":"powerly","c":"powerless","d":"unpower","answer":"3","explain":"\n- To be adj to do sth.\u00a0\n+ Powerless: unable to stop or control something because you do not have the power, strength, or legal right to do so.\u00a0","category":"3","subcategorylv1":"19","subcategorylv2":"23","type":"1"},{"question":"Either my answer or yours ________ wrong.","a":"is","b":"are","c":"has","d":"have","answer":"1","explain":"- The verb form will agree with the pronoun closest to it (yours + singular verb)","category":"3","subcategorylv1":"19","subcategorylv2":"23","type":"1"}]}